One incredible afternoon Napoleon met Wellington . . . at Waterloo.
Waterloo is a history, drama, war film directed by Sergey Bondarchuk.
After defeating France and imprisoning Napoleon on Elba, ending two decades of war, Europe is shocked to
find Napoleon has escaped and has caused the French Army to defect from the King back to him.
The best of the British generals, the Duke of Wellington, beat Napolean's best generals in
Spain and Portugal, but now must beat Napoleon himself with an Anglo Allied army.
Napoleon Bonaparte, played by Rod Steiger.
Arthur Wellesley, Duke of Wellington, played by Christopher Plummer.
Louis XVIII, played by Orson Welles.
General Sir Thomas Picton, played by Jack Hawkins.
Duchess of Richmond, played by Virginia McKenna.
Marshal Michel Ney, played by Dan O'Herlihy.
Waterloo (Russian: Ватерлоо) is a 1970 English-language epic historical drama film
about the Battle of Waterloo, the decisive battle of the Napoleonic Wars.
A co-production between Italy and the Soviet Union, it was directed by
Sergei Bondarchuk and produced by Dino De Laurentiis.
It stars Rod Steiger as Napoleon Bonaparte and
Christopher Plummer as the Duke of Wellington.
Other stars include Jack Hawkins as General Sir Thomas Picton, Virginia McKenna as the Duchess of
Richmond, Dan O'Herlihy as Marshal Ney, and Orson Welles as Louis XVIII of France.
The film is centered not just on the Battle of Waterloo, but also on the
days that led to the campaign known as the Hundred Days.
Steiger and Plummer often narrate sections in voice-over,
presenting thoughts of Napoleon and Wellington.
The film takes a largely neutral stance and portrays many individual leaders and
soldiers on each side, rather than simply focusing on Wellington and Napoleon.
It creates a generally accurate chronology of the events of the battle, the extreme heroism
on each side, and the loss of life suffered by all the participating armies.
The film is most famous for its lavish battle scenes,
shot on-location in Uzhhorod, Ukraine.
Its 17,000 authentically dressed extras, recreating battle scenes with true numbers and
without special effects, remain the largest body of costumed extras in any film.
Despite mixed critical reviews, it won several awards, including BAFTAs for Best Costume
Design and Best Art Direction, and the 1971 David di Donatello for Best Film.
The film explores themes of biography, napoleon
bonaparte, 19th century, waterloo.
The tone is emotional.